Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have a very
advanced lesson for
you all about medicine.
That's right, today
we're going to take a
look at what is very
widely known as Chinese
traditional medicine, so a
very interesting topic in general.
That's right, and for people who use this
they might call it TCM, traditional Chinese
medicine, so remember that
there's that acronym as well.
But let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and when we come back we'll be discussing
some of the important words
and phrases in the dialogue.
What's wrong?
I have a headache.
These past few days
I've been living off
painkillers, man I feel like
my head is going to explode.
You should get acupuncture treatment.
My mom was always having headache issues
and it was acupuncture that cured her.
The results are too
slow, on top of that just
the thought of smoking needles
poking into my flesh frightens me.
They don't just randomly
stick you, they find
your pressure points,
the heat allows the
body to immediately respond to the
treatment restoring the body's cheek.
But I get scared the moment I see a needle.
How could I stand having needles
in my body for hours on end?
The needles are very
thin and as long as the
doctor's technique is
good and the patient
himself is relaxed, it won't hurt, on the
contrary it will actually alleviate pain.
Now there are high-tech needles that are
micro-thin, they don't hurt at all, however
if you are really scared of acupuncture,
scraping or cupping are also options.
Scraping is too terrifying.
When they finish scraping your body
is all red as if you were just tortured.
cupping is the same,
your body ends up with red
circles all over it, looks
like someone beat you up.
This only signifies
that the toxins have left
the body, actually
there's only discomfort
during the treatment process, once
it's over you'll feel very comfortable.
Chinese medicine is
strange, the patients are
already ill and then the
doctor makes them suffer more.
This is the only way to get at the problem,
anyway, if you want to relieve the pain you
are just going to have
to be tough and do it.
Forget it, I don't want to inflict any more
pain on myself, in a little while I'll go
and buy some more
painkillers and take a nap.
Alright, we're back so now obviously we
are talking about what is commonly known as
alternative medicine
because, well, we know
that traditional medicine
nowadays is doctors,
you know, you have
antibiotics, that sort of thing.
And here you're actually
using these techniques
and these different
ways of curing someone.
So the first thing that comes
to mind here is acupuncture.
That's right, so
acupuncture is usually
considered a part of
Chinese medicine and it's
the kind of medicine
that uses needles in
different parts of the
body, so it might look
really scary because
you see people lying
on their stomachs with needles
coming out of their backs.
Right, and those are the
places where they put the
needles in, they're called
pressure points, right?
That's right, and
pressure points are things
that we talk about
with massages as well.
So a good masseuse, a
person who does a massage
will also look for these pressure points,
which are key points on the body, and in
acupuncture they'll put
these needles into those
points as well because
each point relates to
a different part of the body,
like the liver or the kidneys.
Right, so it's actually
very interesting,
the fact that by sticking
a needle in one of
these pressure points
they are curing or
alleviating the pain
of maybe, like you said,
your kidney or your liver
or something like this.
This is a really great word, the word
that you just used to alleviate pain.
Now to alleviate pain
means to make the pain
go away, so we heard
the opposite of that
as well, also at the very
end of today's dialogue.
Right, so the opposite of
alleviate would be to inflict pain.
This is to do pain to
yourself or to someone else.
To cause pain.
To cause pain, so to alleviate is to
take it away, and to inflict is to cause.
Now acupuncture is
very popular, sticking
needles in people's
pressure points, it does seem
like it would hurt, but there are other
ones that maybe are not as widely known.
The next one that we're
going to talk about is scraping.
Scraping, so to scrape is a verb, and you
can scrape the bottom of your plate with
your spoon, or you
can scrape on, you know,
sometimes cats like to
scrape on the furniture,
and they use their claws,
and I make that sound.
But in this case, scraping is a little
bit more, maybe painful sounding.
What do they do in scraping?
So basically, it's the same thing, they use
different tools, and they scrape your body,
they just, I don't
know, basically what I
understand from it is
that they are extracting
the illness by taking
it out of your skin.
So they use what
looks like a small knife,
or like a flat, kind of
sharp blade, and they
actually kind of take off the top
layer of your skin, they scrape it away.
Yeah.
It's very, very painful
from what I've heard,
I've never done it
myself, but as we see
in the dialogue, it does look very, it
looks like you've been hit or treated poorly
at the present or something, because
your skin is red and almost bleeding.
That's right, and another one
that actually looks quite painful
when you see someone after
they've done it is called cupping.
Right.
Now this one you might have seen even in
the last karate kid movie, basically it's a
little round bulb,
or a little round glass
cup, and the doctor,
the Chinese doctor will
light a piece of cotton, and we'll put the
cup over it, and the suction effect that by
putting out the fire
and it sucks up all the
oxygen and everything causes the cup to
suck onto your skin really, really tight.
Yeah, it's like, you pull, you put it on
your skin so it creates a vacuum, right?
There's no air coming in, and that way
the cup, there's no air in, has to pull out
all those chemicals, and those toxins, and
that oil from your skin, and take it away.
Right.
Right, so it's actually
pulling at your skin.
Yeah, and well that's the thing, the vacuum
effect is so great, and pulling it out with
such force that you're actually left with a
big purple or red circle on your skin from,
I guess the blood clot type thing, the fact
that it's caused by it, so you will see
a person's back, maybe,
and they have bruises,
yeah, like six, seven, ten
bruises on their backs.
Although I am told
that even though it's very
painful, and it looks
even more painful, the
effect is that it does
help your circulation,
it helps the blood in your
body move around more freely.
Yeah, I've heard the same
thing, and even though
that it looks painful and it may be painful
while they're doing it, I've heard that
after it's done, even
though it looks like it
should hurt, it looks
like a bruise, it doesn't
hurt like a bruise, so
people don't actually
say, "Oh, you know, don't touch my back, it
really hurts, it doesn't really seem that
way."
Well, and there's an interesting line
in the dialogue that is related to this.
It's about scraping, actually, but
you can say it about cupping as well.
Your body is all red, as
if you were just tortured.
Now, as if you were tortured, or we
could say, as if you were beaten up.
That in this case, was the person tortured?
No.
So it's basically a
relation or making that
relation that your skin
is so bloody that it looks
as if you were tortured, so it seems like
somebody hit you with a whip or something.
It looks like you were
tortured, but you weren't,
so as if is a way for us to make
a comparison or an analogy.
Right.
You can see it in maybe books, you know, so
maybe you would describe a guy saying, "Oh,
he was really angry
as if he had rabies.
" Yeah, it's as if he had rabies, like he
doesn't, but he's acting like he does.
Or maybe you run
into the kitchen and eat
so much food as if you
hadn't eaten in days.
Exactly.
So you have, obviously, but you're
acting like someone who is starving.
So yeah, that is an
interesting way to describe
or to make a connection
between two different things.
And well, Chinese
traditional medicine as
well, very interesting
and historical form of
treating illnesses now,
I'm told that it does
work, even though some
people are very skeptical
about it, and I don't think it's accepted
in the international medical field.
Well, I think that there's a Western
medicine which has its benefits.
You know, you have
penicillin and all of these
different antibiotics to
help us combat different
diseases and bacteria,
but also traditional
Chinese medicine kind
of helps other things.
I think there is a
spirituality, this idea that
we have a chi, there
is a, there are positive
and negative forces in
our bodies, and sometimes
trauma or big events
will make, make that
chi kind of, well, it'll affect it in a
bad way so that she is unbalanced.
And so a lot of this is about
rebalancing your system.
And if you believe that
and you really understand
that, you know,
there are certain forces
inside your body, then I'm sure this kind
of medicine has a positive effect on you.
Right.
I believe that it does
have its ups and downs.
I was very skeptical
about until once,
actually I had a very,
very, very bad headache,
and somebody took and
pushed a pressure point
on my finger on my
thumb for about maybe
one or two minutes and
the headache was gone.
So it was very, I was very much amazed, but
at the same time when people are treated
maybe for, you know,
maybe they can conceive
a baby and they're
doing these rituals or
giving them ginger or different
roots to drink and eat and stuff.
I don't know if that
really does help or
what evidence there is
that it actually does work.
Well, I think that's
something that also
is, is important to
look at on an individual
basis, you know, I
don't think, I don't think
even some Western
medicines help all the
time if you're not in a place where
you believe that it will work, you know.
Yeah, it's, it's very, it's, but the
interesting aspect of it is, of course, so many
years ago, we're talking about hundreds or
thousands of years ago, when there was no
Western medicine and
then people were being
cured and treated by these, by these
techniques which actually worked.
So there is a very interesting
aspect that maybe even Western
medicine can learn from
traditional medicine like this.
Definitely.
So, it's an interesting
topic, Oriental medicine,
Western medicine, but we want
to know what you think about it.
We also want to know,
in your home country,
do you have a traditional
kind of medicine or
any medical alternatives
to Western medicine
let us know, our website
is www.engushpod.com.
Alright, we'll see you guys there.
Bye.